字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
God.
神啊
Is it truly your will that we must always remain pure?
我們一定要永遠活得這麼聖潔嗎？
Is it true?
這是真的嗎？
That those who ignore your will, even angels, are to be punished?
那些不遵守祢旨意的人 就算是天使，也要遭受懲罰？
That is what my father says.
爸爸是這麼說的
Someone like me
像我這樣的人
does not understand all your thoughts.
不懂祢的想法
But to me your heavenly kingdom
我只是覺得祢的天堂離我很遠
Anne!
安！
Come help with preparing dinner!
過來幫我準備晚餐！
All right! I'll be right there.
好，馬上過去
You…
祢…
You, who are in Heaven…
祢安坐於天堂
watching over all of us down here.
看著我們的一舉一動
To me…
對我來說
it is a burden.
是種負擔
O Lord.
耶和華啊
Return us
求祢使我們向祢回轉
so that we may be reborn.
我們便得回轉
Redeem our present days
求祢復新我們的日子，像古時一樣
So what you're saying, father…
神父，你的意思是…
It's like
是那個意思吧！
what my older brother and I have.
我和我哥的關係就是這樣
We've done everything together since we were kids.
我們從小不管做什麼事情都在一起
We grew up helping each other out.
相互扶持到現在
Our teamwork on the battlefield is second to none.
我們戰場上的合作不會輸人
Right?
對吧？
We know what the other's thinking.
我們知道對方在想什麼
He's the only one I trust to watch my back.
我只信任他替我守住後方
The trust we have can't be traded for silver.
我們之間的信任連銀子也換不來 對吧，老哥？
That's right, Brother.
沒錯，老弟
Well, it depends how much.
不過還是要看多少錢啊
The bond of brothers!
兄弟之情啊！
What do you think?
-怎麼樣？
Is this it?
-是這個嗎？
I don't know.
我不知道，也許吧
But that is quite different from how I imagine love.
不過這跟我想像的愛完全不同
Now see here, father.
我說神父啊
You've never been to battle and have no idea how amazing it is.
你從沒上過戰場 所以不知道我們的兄弟情有多厲害
We're a superb duo in a cutthroat world.
在這攸關生死的世界，我們合作無間
Could your love do that?
你能做到嗎？
I think it's wonderful.
我覺得很美好
You brothers have something that is irreplaceable.
你們的兄弟情是無可取代的
Now then,
那麼
if we stood on the field of battle,
如果我上了戰場
would you make the effort to watch my back?
你會在後方保護我嗎？
I do it for him because he's my brother.
他是我親兄弟，我才這麼做的
I wouldn't let a drunk monk watch my back.
我才不會將性命交給一個基督徒酒鬼
Certainly not.
那是當然的
That's the difference.
所以才不一樣
Besides, take a look at yourself.
而且你自己又怎麼說？
You seem to drink a whole lot.
你好像很愛喝酒
Is that wine your love?
酒對你來說是“愛”嗎？
No.
不是
I don't drink because I love it.
我喝酒並不是因為我愛喝
What?
什麼？
Then don't drink it.
那就別喝啊
I'm sorry.
對不起
He makes no sense.
他說的很不合理
So, you like things that make no sense? Well, then how about this one?
所以你喜歡不合理的事情？
It's a story we veterans still tell.
這是很久以前的事 但老成員還是很常提起
A while back, we attacked a ship in the Faroe Islands.
很久以前 我們在法羅群島襲擊了一艘船
The ship had one warrior on it.
那艘船上有一名戰士
He was extraordinarily strong.
他超強的
We all attacked him at once,
我們所有人一起上
but before we knew it, he'd laid out 30 of us with just his bare fists.
結果他一下子就徒手打倒了30人
His bare fists!
徒手耶！
Eventually, our arrows put him down.
雖然我們最後還是放箭殺了他
When we checked the damage, strangely there were no fatalities.
但後來檢查人員傷亡時 發現我們沒有人死亡
Now that's a mystery.
不知道那是怎麼回事
He did wield a sword in the end.
他有佩劍吧？
Perhaps he realized he'd underestimated us?
也許他太小看我們了？
Well, that's insulting.
如果是這樣，那簡直是侮辱
Honor among warriors is of the--
戰士之間的禮儀是…
Did that man…
那個人
do anything else?
還有做別的事嗎？
What was his name?
他叫什麼名字？
I…
我不知道他的名字
I seem that
做事毫無道理的人 才會對彼此有興趣吧
That man also said something peculiar.
那個人也說了奇怪的話
"A true warrior needs no sword."
“真正的戰士不需要劍”
Or something like that.
那類的話
You feeling unwell, monk?
基督徒，你搞什麼？
Hey, where are you going?
你…要去哪裡？
What is it, monk?
怎麼了，基督徒？
Is that what you mean by "love"?
是那個嗎？那是“愛”嗎？
A true warrior…
真正的戰士…
needs no sword.
不需要劍
Don't blame me for this weather.
別跟我抱怨天氣
I sail ships.
我是水手
I know the sea. This land weather is not my specialty.
海上的氣象我很熟 但陸上的天氣我摸不著頭緒
To predict how the winter will be ahead of time is asking too much of me.
誰想得到入冬之後雪還會下這麼大
That's not what I said.
我不是這個意思
I said that it seems that your luck is beginning to run out.
我只是說你不再走運了
You changed course to avoid the snow and now look.
你為了避雪而繞道，結果卻這樣
Your men are considerably agitated.
你的手下都躁動不安
My men have survived the carnage of war.
我的手下在戰爭中存活下來
Something like this won't scare them away.
這點小事嚇不了他們的
They're doing just as they're told. No questions asked.
他們聽令做事，不問第二句話
Turn back.
回威爾斯吧 不可能穿越麥西亞王國了
If we push back through the snow, we'll have to abandon our plunder.
如果要冒雪前進，就得丟棄戰利品
My men wouldn't like that.
我的手下不會願意的
Regardless of what we do, camping here is impossible.
不管怎麼做
Askeladd, the preparations are complete.
阿謝拉特
We can go.
我們可以走了
Finally.
好
Askeladd.
阿謝拉特
When your luck runs out, everything you plan will come to ruin.
運氣用光時，做什麼都不會順的
Ragnar.
拉古納爾
Are you suddenly faint-of-heart?
你為什麼如此猶豫不決？
The raiding and plundering of villages
襲擊、掠奪村莊
is one of our Nordic traditions.
是我們北方人的傳統啊
Our Father who art in heaven, hallowed be thy name.
我們在天上的父，願祢的名被尊為聖
Give us this day our daily bread,
今天也請賜予我們食糧
and forgive us our trespasses,
赦免我們的罪債 如同我們饒恕了得罪我們的人
And lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil.
不要讓我們陷入試探 救我們脫離那惡者
For thine is the kingdom
因為國度、權柄、榮耀 全是祢的，直到永遠
Amen.
阿們
Amen!
-阿們！
Hey, Papa.
爸爸
Why do we always pray?
為什麼我們總是在禱告？
Because Jesus told us to.
因為耶穌要我們禱告
What Jesus says is never wrong.
耶穌的話永遠不會錯
What happens if we don't pray?
不禱告會怎麼樣？
If you don't believe, then you'll go to Hell when you die.
如果不虔誠，那你死後會下地獄
That's right.
沒錯
Hell is a scary place where the Devil looms.
地獄裡有很多惡魔喔
You don't like the Devil, do you?
你不喜歡惡魔吧？
I'm scared of the Devil.
我很怕惡魔
Yes, me too.
對，我也是
But good children who pray will go to Heaven.
但認真禱告的好孩子會上天堂
Remember that.
記住這一點
It doesn't make sense to me.
這對我來說不合理
That someday we'll all have to go to Heaven or Hell.
我們很快就會上天堂或下地獄 這種話聽起來很不合理
I would hate for our family to be separated.
我不希望跟家人分開
But Father, why would God suddenly wish to pass judgment on the whole world?
不過，爸爸
It's not suddenly.
不是突然的
It was decided a long time ago
這是很久以前就決定的
that it would happen 1,000 years after the resurrection of Jesus.
審判日會在耶穌復活後一千年發生
In other words, 20 years from now.
也就是20年後
By God's judgment, all that is evil will go to Hell.
神會審判這個世界 壞人全都會下地獄
I know!
我知道！
The evil ones are the Danes!
壞人就是丹麥人！
That's right! They are pure evil.
沒錯，他們壞透了
I am sure that God foresaw their appearance in the world.
神一定知道世上會出現那種人
Listen, you must make sure to follow the teachings of Jesus well.
聽好了，你一定要聽從耶穌的教誨…
Anne?
安？
I need to pee.
我要去尿尿
What do I do?
我該怎麼辦？
I'm scared of the Devil!
我很怕惡魔！
But it's so pretty.
但這真的好漂亮
I put it on again…
我又戴上了
I wonder how much this ring is worth.
不知道這枚戒指值多少錢
If I pay for it now, I wonder if God will forgive me.
如果我現在付錢 不知道神會不會寬恕我
I must have been tempted by the Devil.
我一定是被惡魔誘惑了
I have no money.
我沒有錢
I shouldn't have even gone to the market to look.
所以不應該去市場的
Bad children like me will surely go to Hell on Judgment Day.
像我這樣的壞孩子 在審判日一定會下地獄
I'm certain I'll be the only one in the family…
我一定是家中唯一一個
who won't go to Heaven.
無法上天堂的人
And it even looks good on my left hand!
戴在左手也很好看！
Who are they?
他們是誰？
What a silly face!
這張臉真傻！
Me too!
我也要玩…
Don't you remember what I said?
你們沒聽到我剛才說的嗎？
If you don't behave, God will punish…
如果不乖，神會懲罰…
So.
喂
I found dinner.
我找到晚餐了
But thou hast utterly rejected us; thou art very wroth against us.
（難道你完全棄絕了我們）
Everyone! Please run!
大家快逃！
The village is under attack!
有人要攻擊村子…
-The Danes are coming! -Shut up, you damn monk!
-丹麥人來… -閉嘴，你這該死的基督徒！
Do you want to die?
你想死嗎？
-It's warm in here. -I feel revived.
裡面好暖和
What are you doing here?
你們突然進來做什麼…
Barley milk porridge and some dried meat.
大麥牛奶粥和一些肉乾
Shame, there's onions in it.
天啊，裡面有洋蔥
Confiscate anything that could be a weapon.
喂，可以當武器的東西通通沒收
Got it.
好
Disgusting. You're eating some awful slop.
真噁心，這麼難吃的東西 你們吃得下去？
Stop that!
-住手 -喂
What is wrong with you?
你們有什麼毛病？
Wasting food like that.
竟然這樣糟蹋食物
You'll be punish!
你會受懲罰…
Are you all right?
妳沒事吧？喂！
Let's see. How do you say it in English again?
我想想，英格蘭話是怎麼說的？
"Give us all your food or…"
“把食物…”
Oh, that's right.
對喔
-Come on! -You, old man.
-喂，醒醒啊 -喂，老頭
-Over here.
-喂！ -看我這裡
Give me all your food.
把食物通通給我
Or I'll kill you.
不然我就殺了你
Here's one more.
我看看，這個…
Is this all?
就這樣？
If food for two kids equals one adult, then that's 50 people.
就算兩個小孩算成一個大人 那一共也才50人
That leaves us with food for 50 people to last the winter.
這樣過冬的糧食只有50人份
It's not enough for 104 warriors.
不夠104名戰士吃
What do I do?
我該怎麼辦？
Everyone has been captured. What should I do?
大家都被抓了，我該怎麼辦？
Father!
神父！
As teacher to His Highness, you are a welcome guest of our group.
身為王子殿下的老師 你也算是我們軍隊的客人
We will forgive you this one time.
我們這次就原諒你
But if you interfere again, we will kill you on the spot.
但你要是敢再礙事，我會當場殺了你
I've never been fond monks anyway.
我本來就討厭基督徒
Danes?
是丹麥人嗎？
Is there anyone among you who speaks our language?
有人會說我們的語言嗎？
I beg of you! Half of the food!
我求你們！一半的食物就好
Please, leave us at least half!
請留下至少一半的食物就好！
We can still make it through winter with only half.
有一半就能勉強過冬了
I have a young child!
我家有寶寶！
Please!
求求你們！
A young child?
寶寶？還真是傷腦筋
Don't worry.
別擔心
I've a plan for you all.
我替你們想好了
You needn't worry about surviving the winter.
你們不必擔心過冬的問題了
Really?
真的嗎？你是說真的？
I do.
是的
You needn't worry about this or any other winter.
你們也不用擔心明年冬天或後年冬天
We will liberate you from your agony.
我會替你們從痛苦中解脫
What?
什麼？
Askeladd.
阿謝拉特，他們是平民
Even if we spare them, they'll starve without food.
就算饒了他們，他們也沒食物可以吃
If even one escapes, they'll reveal our position to the enemy.
要是有人逃跑
I can't let that happen.
不能讓這種事情發生
How's it going? Have you dug the hole?
怎麼樣？挖好洞了嗎？
Yes. We can probably cram in 62 of them.
挖好了，可以塞得下62個人
Askeladd!
阿謝拉特
These people are Christians!
他們是基督徒！
What about it?
那又怎樣？
We're doing all this for the prince.
為了王子殿下，這是最好的辦法
All right.
好，還有人有問題嗎？
No one?
沒人吧？
In that case,
好
the order is…
這樣的話，來人啊
kill them all.
殺了他們
God.
神啊
Are you watching?
祢正在看嗎？
Did Father, Mother, Grandfather,
爸爸、媽媽、爺爺
my younger brothers and sisters…
和弟弟妹妹
arrive to you in Heaven?
上天堂了嗎？
I guess it is not my fate to be called up there after all.
我想我不會被召喚上去了
Of course not.
當然不會
Nevertheless…
但是…
my heart races so.
我好興奮
I cannot believe…
我沒想到
I cannot believe that such terrible men exist in the world.
世界上有這麼壞的人存在
I cannot believe…
我不敢相信
that there are men who fear not your punishment.
竟然有人不怕祢的懲罰
Just as the time I stole this ring…
就像我偷了這枚戒指一樣
my heart…
我現在…
races so fast.
也好興奮